should I worry about getting on trt with
hereditary hemocromatosis
so arguably uh increasing testosterone
will be therapeutic for hemocromatosis
because it will reduce fertin levels in
everyone so this gentleman it would be
important if he's regularly getting
floto you know every eight weeks he
might find that if he goes on
testosterone and continues that schedule
if that brings him into a 50 to 100
range for fertin that could make him
anemic because testosterone will
increase red blood cell production by
utilizing more fartin so I find that
when guys have like half the
hemocromatosis genes like when they've
only got uh one S&P for it and they
don't have the full-blown presentation a
lot of the time trt will resolve their
need to flotto so it can be very
therapeutic for hemocromatosis but if
someone's got full-blown hemocromatosis
it's not contraindicated but it's
something that will likely change their
requirement for blood donation and that
needs to be monitored both make sure
that it doesn't get too high or too low
I have seen guys over flotto on trt all
the time and it leads to anemic symptoms
which is basically uh nulls and voids
the benefits of their trt treatment so
every eight weeks is a very high
frequency for floto so I would be uh
testing levels before getting a flotto
done after initiating trt to make sure
that levels aren't going to get tanked
and you might find that you can push
push that frequency back uh to maybe
every 10 weeks 12 weeks 16 weeks uh
depending on you know where where that
individual's level sit
[Music]